Hello everyone. So, welcome. So we are going to continue our lecture on virtual memory.
大家好。所以，欢迎大家。我们将继续进行关于虚拟内存的讲座。
And we are going to start discussion on caching and TLBs, which stands for translation lookaside
缓存和TLB（翻译后备缓冲）的讨论即将开始。
buffers.
缓冲区。
So if you recall, address translation as a name implies, it's about translating the addresses
所以如果你还记得的话，地址转换正如其名，是关于将地址进行翻译的。
which are viewed by the application by the CPUs into physical addresses. And there are
由CPU将其视为物理地址的应用程序所查看的地址。而且还有...
a couple of reasons why we want to have these different kind of addresses for the application
我们希望为应用程序使用不同类型的地址有几个原因：
1. 隔离性：通过使用不同类型的地址，我们可以将应用程序的不同部分隔离开来，以便更好地管理和维护。例如，我们可以将数据库服务器的地址与前端服务器的地址分开，以确保它们之间的通信不会相互干扰。
2. 安全性：使用不同类型的地址可以增强应用程序的安全性。例如，我们可以将敏感数据的地址与公共访问的地址分开，以减少潜在的安全风险。
3. 可扩展性：通过为应用程序使用不同类型的地址，我们可以更轻松地扩展应用程序的功能和规模。例如，我们可以为不同的功能模块分配不同的地址，以便在需要时可以独立地扩展或缩小它们。
总之，使用不同类型的地址可以提供更好的隔离性、安全性和可扩展性，以满足应用程序的需求。
and versus the physical addresses. And some of them are about providing the illusion to
和物理地址相比。其中一些是关于提供幻觉的。
each application, it has its own machine, its own resources, including the memory, which
每个应用程序都有自己的机器，自己的资源，包括内存。
means that then you need to map the address space of each of the application in the same
意味着你需要将每个应用程序的地址空间映射到相同的位置。
physical space, which is physical memory. And also another reason is protection because
物理空间，即物理内存。另一个原因是保护。
you want to protect the address space of one application from another. And also sharing,
你想保护一个应用程序的地址空间不被其他应用程序访问。同时也想实现共享。
controlled sharing, if you remember, in which actually some parts of the address space you
受控共享，如果你还记得的话，实际上是指地址空间的某些部分。
want to be shared. For instance, the address space, which contains a code of a shared library,
希望被共享。例如，地址空间中包含了一个共享库的代码。
of a library, which is a code of a library, which is used by two applications like Windows
一个图书馆的代码，被两个应用程序使用，类似于Windows。
library on your own Windows machine, you do not want to replicate that code in each application,
在您自己的Windows机器上创建一个库，您不想在每个应用程序中复制该代码。
you want to share that code. And typically the sharing happens, it's handled by one of
你想分享那段代码。通常情况下，分享是由其中一个人处理的。
these components, a chip, which is called memory management unit. So this was originally
这些组件中有一个芯片，被称为内存管理单元。所以这原本是
was a standard on chip, which was you put near your, between the processor and the memory.
芯片上有一个标准，你将其放置在处理器和内存之间。
But of course, in the modern processors, it's just a component of that processor. And one
当然，在现代处理器中，它只是处理器的一个组件。而且一个
of the techniques to do address translation was a segment, we're using multi-segment model.
地址转换的技术之一是分段，我们正在使用多段模型。
And in this case, if you remember, each segment is represented by a base and a limit. And
在这种情况下，如果你记得的话，每个段都由一个基址和一个限长表示。而且
now the virtual address, the address, which is seen by the CPU and as seen by the application,
现在是虚拟地址，即CPU看到的地址，也是应用程序看到的地址。
is split into two. The first part, the first few bits represent an index in the segment
被分成两部分。第一部分，前几个位表示段中的索引。
table. And then there is an offset. So when you have a virtual address, you look at the
表格。然后有一个偏移量。所以当你有一个虚拟地址时，你查看的是表格。
first field, which is a segment number, the first bits represent the segment number, use
第一个字段是段号，前几位表示段号，使用。
that to index into segment table. And then in that segment table, you are going to find
将其用作索引进入段表。然后在该段表中，您将找到
the base of the segment and the limit. And you are going to compute the physical address
段的基址和限制。你将要计算物理地址。
by adding the offset, which is the second field in the virtual address to the base,
通过将虚拟地址中的第二个字段（偏移量）与基址相加，
the segment base. And of course, you are also going to check whether the address is generated
段基址。当然，你还要检查地址是否已生成。
is less than the limit. So it's within the segment. You also have in some architecture,
小于限制。所以它在该段内。你还在一些架构中，
actually in Intel x86, instead of having the first bits in the address, in the virtual
实际上，在Intel x86架构中，与其在地址中使用前几位，更准确地说，在虚拟地址中使用的是最后几位。
address, it's presenting the base indexing into the segment table. You have just a bunch
地址，它表示对段表的基本索引。你只是有一堆
of segments. You have initially have four segments and these segments are base segments
的片段。你最初有四个片段，这些片段是基础片段。
are stored in special registers like ES, this is S is for the stack and three other registers.
存储在特殊寄存器中，如ES，其中S代表栈和其他三个寄存器。
Okay. And then you compute the address by taking the virtual address and you are going
好的。然后你通过取虚拟地址来计算地址。
to add it to the segment register. And that's how you are going to compute the physical
将其添加到段寄存器中。这就是你要计算物理地址的方法。
address. Finally, there is a bit valid or not valid. And this is one use of this one
地址。最后，有一点有效或无效。这是这个的一个用法。
is that not all segments of all applications can fit in the physical memory at the same
这意味着并非所有应用程序的所有段都能同时适应物理内存。
time. So when you run out of space in the physical memory and you want to load your
时间。所以当你的物理内存空间用完了，你想要加载你的
certain new application and your program, you need to allocate space in the physical
某些新的应用程序和您的程序需要在物理内存中分配空间。
memory for that new program, the segments of the new program. You may take one of the
内存用于那个新程序，新程序的段。你可以选择其中一个。
existing segments of an application which doesn't run and you are going to store it
现有的应用程序部分无法运行，您打算将其存储起来。
on the disk. Okay. And so then for the segment is no longer in memory. So then you can say
在磁盘上。好的。所以，对于该段落不再在内存中。那么你可以说什么？
it's not, you can use this bit to specify that. So whenever next time when you are looking
这不是，你可以使用这一部分来指定。所以下次当你在寻找的时候，无论什么时候，你都可以使用它。
for something in that segment, then you are going to get an exception and the exception
如果在那个部分中有某个东西，那么你将会得到一个异常和这个异常。
is going to be treated by the operating system and the operating system will bring the segment
将由操作系统处理，并且操作系统将引入该段。
from the disk to memory before executing that instruction. Okay. So this is some examples.
从磁盘加载到内存，然后执行该指令。好的。这是一些例子。
So here it's a simple, an example of an architecture is four segments. The address is 16 bits. The
所以这里是一个简单的例子，一个体系结构由四个段组成。地址是16位。
first two bits of the address are used to specify the segment number. And because we
前两位地址用于指定段号。而且因为我们
have four segments, we need only two bits. So these are bits 15 and 14 and the rest of
有四个段，我们只需要两个位。所以这些是第15位和第14位，其余的是什么？
these from 13 to zero represent the offset. On the left hand side, you can see the address
这些从13到零代表偏移量。在左边，你可以看到地址。
space, the virtual address space. So as seen by the processor, by the application. And
空间，虚拟地址空间。所以从处理器和应用程序的角度来看。
we have our traditional four segments, the code segments, the data, the stack segments,
我们有我们的传统四个段，代码段，数据段，栈段，
and this is also, we added a shared segment. Think about this is either the data or the
这也是我们添加的一个共享段。考虑一下，这既可以是数据，也可以是
code which you may want to share with another application. So here in green, you have the
可能想要与另一个应用程序共享的代码。所以在这里，你有绿色的。
tables, the segment table, again, four entries for code, data, shared and the stack. And
表格，段表，再次，四个条目分别用于代码、数据、共享和堆栈。
you see you have the base and the limit for each of these segments. So now let's see what
你可以看到每个片段都有基准和限制。现在让我们看看接下来会发生什么。
happens. So for instance, and on the right hand side, you have the physical address.
发生了。例如，在右侧，您有物理地址。
For simplicity in this case, the physical address and the virtual address spaces, they
为了简化起见，在这种情况下，物理地址和虚拟地址空间，它们
have the same size. Okay. So say you are going from the code, you are going to execute the
具有相同的大小。好的。所以假设你正在从代码中执行。
instruction in the code segment. And so where is that going to be mapped in the physical
指令在代码段中。那么它将映射到物理内存的哪个位置呢？
address space? Well, if you look about in the segment table, because the first two bits
地址空间？嗯，如果你在段表中查找，因为前两位是
of everything in the code segment are zero. So therefore you are going to identify the
代码段中的所有内容都是零。因此，你将要识别出这些内容。
first entry in the segment table and you have a base of 4,000 in hexa decimal format. So
在段表中的第一个条目中，你有一个以十六进制格式表示的基地址为4,000。所以
therefore you have to add 4,000 to every address, the virtual address is a code segment and
因此，您需要将4,000添加到每个地址上，虚拟地址是一个代码段，而且
to get the corresponding physical address for the code in the physical address space.
获取代码在物理地址空间中的相应物理地址。
Okay. Then for the data, the data starts in the virtual address space at 4,000. This means
好的。那么对于数据，数据从虚拟地址空间的4,000开始。这意味着
that what are the first two bits of any address in the data segment? Why don't you tell me?
数据段中任何地址的前两位是什么？为什么你不告诉我呢？
It should be a very simple answer here. So the first, you have 16 bits. When we use a
十六位二进制数可以表示的最大十进制数是65535。
hexadecimal representation, right? Four bits represent one digit. So now we have four here
十六进制表示法，对吗？四位二进制数表示一个数字。所以现在我们这里有四个。
first. What does it mean? What are the first four bits representing the four? How do you
首先，"first" 是什么意思？前四位代表了什么？你是如何解释这四个位的含义的？
write four in binary representation? Okay. So here it is. I'm writing this in our chat.
四的二进制表示是"100"。
So four in binary representation, if you want to represent it using four bits, it's what?
所以四的二进制表示，如果你想用四位表示它，是什么？
0, 1, 0, 0, right? This is it, right? It's 1, 0, 0 is four in the binary representation,
是的，这是对的。它的二进制表示中，1, 0, 0代表的是四。
which means that the first two bits for any address in the data segments are one. The
这意味着数据段中任何地址的前两位都是1。
segment number here is what? 0, 1. Now it's not 0, 0, 1. It's 0, 1 because it's only the
段落编号是什么？0，1。现在不是0，0，1了。现在是0，1，因为只有
first bits. But it is correct, you know, it can move. Okay. So it's 0, 1. This is what
首先是位。但是它是正确的，你知道，它可以移动。好的。所以它是0，1。这就是
you have, right? So therefore, to translate any address in the data segment, what do you
你有吗？所以，为了翻译数据段中的任何地址，你需要做什么？
need to do? You go to the second entry in the segment table, the one which the segment
你需要做什么？你需要去段表中的第二个条目，也就是那个与段相关的条目。
ID number is one. And the base here is 4800. So what you need to do is that you are going
身份证号码是一。这里的基数是4800。所以你需要做的是你要去做什么。
to add in order to translate any address in the data segment, you need to add to it 4800.
为了将数据段中的任何地址进行翻译，你需要将其加上4800。
And for the shared segment, this, you know, the things go similarly. For the shared segment,
对于共享部分，你知道的，情况也是类似的。对于共享部分，
they started at 8000. So the first four bits is 8, 8. What is the binary representation
他们从8000开始。所以前四位是8，8。二进制表示是什么？
of 8? It's exactly. So the first two bits are 1, 0. So the segment number, it's 1, 0
八的二进制表示是1000。所以前两位是1和0。因此，段号是10。
is 2, right? Because you take only the first two bits. And finally, stack C. What is C?
是2，对吗？因为你只取前两位。最后，堆栈C是什么？
The representation, binary representation of C. You should remember this, right? It's
C的表示，二进制表示。你应该记得这个，对吧？
review. It's 1, 1, 0, 0. It's exactly. Very good, right? So the first two bits are 1,
复查一下。是1、1、0、0。完全正确。非常好，对吧？所以前两位是1，
1. So it's 3, number 3. So of course, it's the last entry in the table. And for the stack,
1. 所以是3，数字3。所以当然，它是表格中的最后一项。至于堆栈，
the base is 0, right? So you add the base offset to the base. So we started from 0,
基地址是0，对吗？所以你将基偏移量加到基地址上。所以我们从0开始，
0, 0. Okay. Does it make sense? Okay. Let's look at this other example. By the way, you
0, 0. 好的。这有意义吗？好的。让我们看看另一个例子。顺便说一下，你
should try. These are some very important slides because you may expect not only to
应该试一试。这些幻灯片非常重要，因为你可能不仅仅期望到
understand how the address translation works, which is one of the fundamental mechanisms
理解地址转换的工作原理，这是其中一个基本机制之一。
in used by any in today's processors, leveraged by the operating system to provide virtual
在当今的处理器中，被操作系统利用以提供虚拟化。
memory abstraction, but also because you can expect problems like this in your next meter.
内存抽象，也因为你可以预料到你下一个计量器会出现这样的问题。
Okay. So now let's look at this piece of code and see what happens under the hood. And we
好的。现在让我们来看一下这段代码，看看在幕后发生了什么。然后我们
are assuming this piece of code is going to run on the previous architecture from I just
假设这段代码将在之前的架构上运行，从我刚刚提到的。
showed you in the last slide. Okay. So you have the segment table is the same. And now
在上一张幻灯片中向你展示了。好的。所以你有相同的段表。现在
is a code. So the code starts at 240, right? So basically the entire address is 0, 2, 4,
是一个代码。所以代码从240开始，对吗？所以基本上整个地址是0、2、4。
0, but you don't show the first four bits, which are 0, right? Okay. So now let's see
0，但你没有显示前四位，它们是0，对吗？好的。现在让我们看一下。
what happens. And this is pseudo assembly language code. And let's see what happens
发生了什么。这是伪汇编语言代码。让我们看看会发生什么。
when we type this code. The first instruction is a main. And basically what this instruction
当我们输入这段代码时，第一条指令是一个主函数。基本上，这条指令是用来...
is doing, it loads an address, which is bar X into register A0, right? Now this code is
正在执行的是，它将一个地址加载到寄存器A0中，这个地址是bar X，对吗？现在这段代码是...
run in the user process, the user process, see virtual addresses. So all the addresses
在用户进程中运行，用户进程可以看到虚拟地址。因此所有的地址都是虚拟地址。
you see here are virtual addresses. Okay. But now the code and the data, they are actually
你看，这里是虚拟地址。好的。但是现在代码和数据，它们实际上是什么？
stored in the physical memory. So in order to read the instructions and access the data,
存储在物理内存中。因此，为了读取指令和访问数据，
we need to translate the virtual addresses to the physical address. Okay. So the address,
我们需要将虚拟地址转换为物理地址。好的。所以这个地址，
the instruction, first we need to fetch the instruction in order to execute the instructions.
首先，我们需要获取指令以便执行指令。
The instruction again is in physical memory. So the address, the virtual address, it's
指令再次存储在物理内存中。因此，地址，虚拟地址，它的
0, 2, 4, 0, like we discussed. And here it's a binary representation of the address. So
0, 2, 4, 0, 就像我们讨论过的那样。这里是地址的二进制表示。所以
the first two bits are 0. So the segment ID, the segment number is 0. So therefore, in
前两位是0。因此，段ID和段号都是0。因此，在...中，
order to translate this address, virtual address, 2, 4, 0, to a physical address, we need to
为了将这个虚拟地址2, 4, 0转换为物理地址，我们需要
add the base address corresponding to the segment. So the base is 4,000 and the virtual
将基地址添加到对应的段。所以基地址是4,000，虚拟地址是
offset, right, is 2, 4, 0, right? The virtual offset. The offset is the black bits in the
偏移量，正确的是2、4、0，对吗？虚拟偏移量。偏移量指的是黑色位。
address. The bits encoding the segment identifier are the green bits, obviously. Okay. So you
地址。编码段标识符的位是绿色的位，显然。好的。那么你想要我翻译成英文吗？
have to add all the offset, which is 2, 4, 0, to 4,000, which is a base. And therefore
必须将所有的偏移量，即2、4、0，加到基数4,000上。因此，
you are going to get the physical address 4,240. And now you are going to use this address
你将得到物理地址4,240。现在你将使用这个地址。
to fetch the instruction from the memory. And the instruction is basically, like I told
从内存中获取指令。而这个指令基本上就像我说的那样。
you, is to load the address, which is VAREX address, which is 4050, this is the virtual
你需要加载的地址是VAREX地址，它是4050，这是虚拟地址。
address, into register A0. Now, after that, you execute the instruction, you would know
将地址存入寄存器A0。然后，在执行该指令之后，你就会知道。
very well what happens. Next, the program counter, it's incremented by 4, right? Because
非常好，接下来，程序计数器会加4，对吗？因为
here assuming that there are instructions, they occupy 4 bytes. Okay. The next instruction
在这里假设有指令，它们占据4个字节。好的。下一条指令是什么？
address is 244. Okay. So let's execute the next instruction. It's again, in the next
地址是244。好的。那么让我们执行下一条指令。它又是在下一个位置。
instruction, you are going to see, you have now the address is 244, like I mentioned.
指示，你即将看到，你现在的地址是244，就像我之前提到的一样。
Again, the physical, if you look at the, this will also be in the code segment. So you need
再次，如果你看一下物理部分，这也将在代码段中。所以你需要
to add the base, which is 4,000. The physical address will be 4244. And you are going to
将基数加上，基数是4,000。物理地址将是4244。然后你要做什么？
get the next instruction, which is gel, to jump to this string length address label.
获取下一条指令，即gel，以跳转到该字符串长度地址标签。
And this is exactly what you do it. But before jumping, here we store the return address.
这就是你所做的。但在跳转之前，我们会存储返回地址。
So after we execute the function string length, we need to return where? To the next instruction
所以在执行字符串长度函数之后，我们需要返回到哪里？返回到下一条指令。
after the jump. The next instruction after the jump would be 0x248. Okay. So therefore
跳转之后。跳转之后的下一条指令将是0x248。好的。因此，
we are going to, we assume here that we have a return address registers, which stores a
我们假设这里有一个返回地址寄存器，它存储了一个返回地址。
return address. So we are going to load into the return address 0248. And this is done
返回地址。所以我们将要加载到返回地址中的值是0248。这样做是为了
automatically by the compiled code, by your application. And then you move in the program
自动由编译后的代码完成，由您的应用程序完成。然后您在程序中移动。
counter, the address where you want to jump. So the address you want to jump, the label
计数器，你想要跳转的地址。所以你想要跳转的地址，就是标签。
string length is corresponding to the address 360. Okay. So you are going to jump there
字符串长度对应地址360。好的。那么你将要跳转到那里。
and you are going to execute that next instruction, which will be the address 360. 360 is again
你将执行下一条指令，该指令的地址将是360。360再次是
is in the segment code. In order to compute the physical address, you are going to add
在段代码中。为了计算物理地址，你需要加上
the base, which is 4,000. So 4,000 plus 360 is 400, 360. And then you are going to read
基数是4,000。所以4,000加360等于4,360。然后你要读的是4,360。
from the physical memory you are going to read. And this instruction is basically initialized
从你将要读取的物理内存中。而且这个指令基本上是初始化的。
this account. So put a zero in a register of zero. Okay. And once you execute that,
这个账户。所以在零的寄存器中放一个零。好的。一旦你执行了这个操作，
to the next instruction.
到下一个指示。
And the next instruction, it's at the address 364.
下一条指令的地址是364。
And this next instruction, it loads
而这个下一个指令，它加载
what is at this particular address, which
这个特定地址上有什么？
is stored in A0.
存储在A0中。
So remember that what we're storing in A0,
所以记住我们在A0中存储的是什么，
it was VARX address.
这是VARX地址。
So this VARX address is 4050.
所以这个VARX地址是4050。
So now we want to load in register T0
现在我们想要将数据加载到寄存器T0中。
the content of the address VARX, so the address 4050.
地址VARX的内容，所以地址4050。
So when we want to do that and we want to access it,
那么当我们想要做那件事并且想要访问它时，
to see what is the content at that virtual address,
查看该虚拟地址上的内容，
the virtual address is 4050.
虚拟地址是4050。
And this is a binary representation.
这是一个二进制表示。
The first two bits are 01.
前两位是01。
So the segment index, which corresponds to this address,
因此，与该地址对应的段索引是多少？
it's 01.
现在是01点。
And therefore, the base address of that segment is 4800.
因此，该段的基地址是4800。
So therefore, you need to add the 4800 to what?
所以，你需要将4800加到什么上面？
To the offset.
对抵消。
So what is the offset here?
这里的偏移量是多少？
The offset here, notice, is 50.
这里的偏移量是50。
So the virtual address is 4050.
所以虚拟地址是4050。
But remember, the first two bits of this address
但请记住，这个地址的前两位
represent the segment ID.
代表段落ID。
That's 01.
那是01。
And the last, in this case, 14 bits,
而最后，在这种情况下，是14位。
represents the offset.
代表偏移量。
But the last 14 bits is 50.
但是最后的14位是50。
So now, the offset is 50.
所以现在，偏移量是50。
It's, again, offset is a black digits, 0 or 1.
这是一个偏移量，再次，它是一个黑色的数字，0或1。
So then you are going to add the offset
那么你打算添加偏移量
to the base, which is 4800.
到基地，即4800。
So the physical address you are going to compute is 4800.
所以你要计算的物理地址是4800。
And you are going to load the byte from that address to T0.
你将从那个地址加载字节到T0。
And you increment the program count.
然后你增加程序计数。
So the main thing to note here is
所以这里需要注意的主要事项是什么？
that everything which is in what the processor sees,
处理器所看到的一切，
everything what is in the registers of the processors,
处理器寄存器中的所有内容，
all these are virtual addresses.
所有这些都是虚拟地址。
The translation happens only where
翻译只会在这里发生。
you are going to access the memory.
你将要访问内存。
So the memory management units really
sits between the arithmetic logical units
坐落在算术逻辑单元之间。
and all the registers and the memory.
以及所有的寄存器和内存。
OK?
好的。
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
OK.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
We spent quite a bit of time on this one.
我们在这个上面花了相当多的时间。
But this is important.
但这很重要。
Please make sure that you understand this example.
请确保你理解这个例子。
OK?
好的。
As you will see from the previous years
正如你从之前的几年中所看到的
and previous exams, you are going
和之前的考试一样，你要去参加考试。
to see a lot of problems like this one.
看到很多类似这样的问题。
So a few things about segmentation.
关于分割，有几点需要注意。
The one problem with the segmentation is nice.
分割的一个问题很好。
It's a very elegant solution.
这是一个非常优雅的解决方案。
But you are going to translate on every instruction,
但是你要在每个指令上都进行翻译。
everything.
一切。
Even fetch an instruction, access, read some data,
即使获取一条指令，访问并读取一些数据，
write some data from the memory.
从内存中写入一些数据。
And virtual address space has holes, right?
虚拟地址空间是有空洞的，对吗？
Because you are not going to use everything in your virtual
因为你不会在你的虚拟空间中使用所有的东西。
address.
地址。
And that's why you use a segmentation in the first part,
而这就是为什么你在第一部分使用了分段的原因，
in the first thing, in the first place.
首先，首先。
Because if you think about if you
因为如果你考虑一下的话，如果你
have the code and the segment, the segment grows.
有代码和片段，片段在增长。
You put the segment as a high addresses
你将该段落放在了高地址处。
because it grows to the smaller, grows downwards
因为它生长得更小，向下生长。
to the smaller addresses.
到较小的地址。
And for instance, the data segment,
例如，数据段，
you have to be as a lower address
你必须扮演一个低级的角色。
because it's growing up.
因为它正在成长。
OK?
好的。
Whilst the stack growing down.
当堆栈向下增长时。
So you need to separate them.
所以你需要将它们分开。
And between them, there is a gap.
他们之间有一个间隙。
So if you have segments, if you don't have the gap,
那么如果你有片段，如果没有间隙的话，
sorry, if you don't have the segments,
抱歉，如果你没有提供具体的句子或段落，
that gap will occupy space in the physical memory.
这个间隙将占据物理内存空间。
Space could have been used, empty space
空间可以被利用，空白的空间。
could have been used to allocate to other processes,
可以用来分配给其他进程。
other applications.
其他应用程序。
However, if I have these two segments now,
然而，如果我现在有这两个部分，
each segment can have--
每个片段可以有--
one segment can have data, one segment can have the stack.
一个段可以存储数据，一个段可以存储栈。
And then they are going to be mapped on the physical memory.
然后它们将被映射到物理内存上。
And the gap, I don't need to map it.
并且这个差距，我不需要去衡量它。
I don't need to just waste the space
我不需要只是浪费空间。
on the physical memory.
在物理内存上。
[SIDE CONVERSATION]
[旁白]
So now, the one thing to notice here is I said,
那么现在，需要注意的一点是我说了，
OK, you allocate segments for the stack and the data.
好的，你为栈和数据分配了段。
But if I allocate, then how--
但是如果我分配，那么怎么样--
allocate the stack at a certain size
将栈分配为特定大小。
and allocate that physical memory for the stack
并将该物理内存分配给堆栈。
at that given size, what happens when the stack grows?
在给定的大小下，当堆栈增长时会发生什么？
And you know that stack grows because as I
而且你知道栈会增长，因为当我
call more functions or say recursive programs,
调用更多的函数或者说递归程序，
every call puts the arguments and puts the return values
每个调用都传递参数并返回值。
and so forth on the stack.
以此类推，依次堆叠。
OK, so how do I do that?
好的，那么我该怎么做呢？
Well, in that sense, when I'm going to browse the stack,
好的，在这个意义上，当我要浏览堆栈时，
for instance, then I'm going to access an address
例如，我要访问一个地址。
outside the limit.
超出限制。
And that will generate an exception.
这将会生成一个异常。
The exception will be treated by the operating system, which
异常将由操作系统处理，
is going to grow the stack, OK, grow the limit
将堆栈增加，好的，增加限制。
or modify the base, and provide more room now
或者修改基础，并提供更多的空间现在。
so the program can add-- put more things on the stack.
所以这个程序可以添加——将更多的东西放入堆栈中。
The same thing for the heap.
堆也是一样的。
OK, there is a question here.
好的，这里有一个问题。
Why did we not translate var x in the first line
我们为什么没有在第一行翻译"var x"？
on the previous slide?
在上一张幻灯片上吗？
So that's a very good question.
那是一个非常好的问题。
Why didn't translate var x?
为什么没有翻译变量x？
Remember what I said?
记得我说的话吗？
Everything that's in the registers is virtual addresses.
所有在寄存器中的内容都是虚拟地址。
These are all virtual addresses.
这些都是虚拟地址。
Because the rule is that the addresses are only
因为规定是地址只能是英文的。
translated when I am going to access a memory.
当我要访问一个记忆时，翻译。
In this case, I am not accessing the memory.
在这种情况下，我没有访问内存。
Var x is just a virtual address, right?
是的，变量x只是一个虚拟地址，对吗？
I don't need to access the memory for that.
我不需要访问内存来做那个。
When I need to access the memory,
当我需要访问内存时，
then I'm going to read the content
那么我要读一下内容。
as a virtual address.
作为一个虚拟地址。
And then I need to find the corresponding physical address.
然后我需要找到相应的物理地址。
And then I do translation.
然后我进行翻译。
But everything that is in the process, in the registers,
但是所有正在进行中的事情，所有在记录中的事情，
it's virtual addresses, basically.
这基本上是虚拟地址。
OK?
好的。
Of course, you need to protect the segment table.
当然，你需要保护段表。
Only the operating system has to be able to modify it.
只有操作系统才能修改它。
And also, it provides--
而且，它还提供了——
the operating system provides protections
操作系统提供保护措施。
for different segments, for instance,
对于不同的细分市场，例如，
to make the code segment being read only.
将代码段设为只读。
OK?
好的。
Now, let's say we do a context switching now.
现在，让我们进行一次上下文切换。
What do we need to save and restore
我们需要保存和恢复什么？
on context switching when you have a process context
当你有一个进程上下文时，进行上下文切换。
Translation: Context switching when you have a process context.
switching?
切换？
So besides, as you know that we need to save a bunch of things
所以除此之外，正如你所知道的，我们需要保存很多东西。
like file identifiers and things like that,
像文件标识符和类似的东西，
the other thing we need to store now is the segment table.
我们现在需要存储的另一件事是段表。
Because the segment table, as I've shown you,
由于分段表，正如我向你展示的那样，
in the previous slide, in the previous examples,
在前一张幻灯片中，在之前的例子中，
you have one segment table per virtual address space.
你每个虚拟地址空间都有一个段表。
And you have one virtual address space
你有一个虚拟地址空间。
per process or per application.
每个进程或每个应用程序。
So when you switch context switch a process,
当你切换上下文时，切换一个进程，
you have also to save the segment table
你还需要保存段表。
because the next process is going to run.
因为接下来的流程即将开始运行。
It's going to have its own segment table.
它将拥有自己的段表。
Also, like I mentioned earlier on,
此外，就像我之前提到的那样，
some of the segments of the process which is no longer
一些不再存在的过程段落
running can be stored on the disk
运行可以存储在磁盘上。
in order to make room for the segments of the next process
为了为下一个流程的部分腾出空间
being run.
正在运行。
This again, this is what happens is that again,
这又是怎么回事，这又发生了什么。
if not all segments within memory,
如果内存中没有所有的段落，
you save them on the disk and you swap them.
你将它们保存在磁盘上并进行交换。
So basically, the P1, say process P1,
所以基本上，P1，也就是进程P1，
it's-- we switch from process P1 to P2.
这是我们从进程P1切换到P2。
Then we can save the segment of process P1 on the disk
然后我们可以将进程P1的片段保存在磁盘上。
to make room for the segment of process P2
为了给进程P2腾出空间。
to be brought in the memory.
被记住。
Of course, if you have to do that,
当然，如果你必须这样做的话，
the context switch cost will grow dramatically.
上下文切换的成本将大幅增加。
So you need to be very careful about what you switch off
所以你需要非常小心地关掉什么
or what you swap out and swap in because you really
或者你交换的是什么，替换进来的是什么，因为你真的很
want to minimize your operation on the disk.
希望尽量减少对磁盘的操作。
And we are going to learn about that the next couple
我们将要学习关于那个的下一对。
of lectures.
讲座的数量。
The problem is fragmentation.
问题是碎片化。
Problems with segmentation, one of the biggest problems
分割问题，其中一个最大的问题之一
is fragmentation because now you need to store different--
碎片化是因为现在你需要存储不同的--
you need to be able to have to store
你需要有一个储存的能力。
and to fit segments of different sizes in memory.
并且适应不同大小的片段存储在内存中。
And if you remember the last lecture,
如果你还记得上一堂课的话，
we had an example in which you leave a lot of gaps.
我们有一个例子，你在其中留下了很多空白。
And you can get to a point in which you have many gaps
而且你可能会遇到很多空白的地方。
in the physical memory, but none of the gaps
在物理内存中，但没有任何间隙。
can be big enough to store a new segment,
可以足够大以存储一个新的片段。
despite the fact that if you add them, all the gaps--
尽管如果你把它们加在一起，所有的间隙--
it's much, much more than what is needed by one--
这远远超出了一个人所需的。
by that segment.
通过那个部分。
Think about you have 100 gaps.
想象一下你有100个间隙。
Each gap is 1 gigabyte.
每个间隔是1千兆字节。
And so you have 100 gigabytes in total of available memory.
所以你总共有100千兆字节的可用内存。
But now you have one segment which requires 2 gigabytes.
但是现在你有一个片段需要2千兆字节。
So you have plenty of available space,
所以你有很多可用的空间，
but none of the available spaces,
但是没有任何可用的空间，
contiguous spaces is large enough
连续的空间足够大。
to store that segment, 2 gigabyte segment.
存储该片段，2千兆字节的片段。
OK.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
So if you do that, you can take one
那么，如果你这样做，你可以拿一个。
of the segments which are there to addition
这里有一些需要添加的片段。
to one of these 1 gigabyte gap.
到这些1千兆字节的间隙之一。
And you are going to store on the disk.
你将要存储在磁盘上。
You are swapping out to make more room.
你正在更换以腾出更多空间。
Or you can move segments around.
或者你可以移动片段。
OK?
好的。
So there are two kinds of fragmentations.
所以有两种类型的分裂。
Both of them waste space.
两者都浪费空间。
Internal fragmentation, you don't need all the memory
内部碎片，你不需要所有的内存
within allocated chunks.
在分配的块内。
And this is also--
这也是--
and then external, which is free gaps within allocated chunks.
然后是外部的，即分配块内的空闲空间。
So what in the example I mentioned to you,
所以，在我给你举的例子中，
I was talking about the external fragmentation.
我在谈论外部碎片化。
OK?
好的。
And next, we are going to talk also
接下来，我们还要谈论
about internal fragmentation.
关于内部碎片化。
OK.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
So basically, this is about another view
所以基本上，这是关于另一个观点。
about the general--
关于将军--
how the address translation happens.
地址转换是如何发生的。
This providing a little more intuition
这提供了一点更直观的理解。
by showing two virtual address spaces mapped
通过展示两个虚拟地址空间的映射
to the same physical address space.
到相同的物理地址空间。
OK?
好的。
And these programs 1 and programs 2,
这些程序1和程序2，
or this process 1 and process 2, the virtual address
或者这个过程1和过程2，虚拟地址
spaces to each of them can look absolutely identical.
每个空间看起来都完全相同。
Think about you're on the same application, two instances
想象一下，你在同一个应用程序上，有两个实例。
of the same application.
相同的应用程序。
But of course, the translation, while in the virtual space
当然，翻译是在虚拟空间中进行的。
are identical, you have in both virtual spaces
是一样的，在两个虚拟空间中都有。
the same thing at the same addresses, virtual addresses.
相同的事情在相同的地址上，虚拟地址。
When you are going to map these virtual addresses
当你要映射这些虚拟地址时
to the physical address space, when
到物理地址空间时，
you are going to translate them, you
你将要翻译它们，你。
are going to translate in such a way
你会以这样的方式进行翻译吗？
that they are not going to conflict.
他们不会发生冲突。
So now, with segmentation, we have
所以现在，有了分割，我们有了
this external fragmentation.
这是外部碎片化。
And sometimes, it's harder to allocate storage
有时候，分配存储空间更加困难。
to variable size chunks.
将其分成可变大小的块。
So there is a solution for that.
那么，对此有一个解决方案。
And a solution for that, which is very simple,
而且，这个解决方案非常简单，
is about instead of allocating variable size chunks,
是指不再分配变量大小的块，
you allocate fixed size chunks.
你分配固定大小的块。
And these are called pages.
这些被称为页面。
So every chunk of physical memory
所以每一块物理内存
is equivalent to the same that it has the same size.
等价于具有相同大小。
And this can allow you to simplify a lot of things.
这样可以让你简化很多事情。
For instance, how do you handle allocation?
例如，你如何处理分配？
So one way to handle the allocation
所以处理分配的一种方法是
is to have a bit vector.
是要有一个位向量。
And each bit in the vector represent one page.
每个向量中的每一位代表一页。
And the value 0 is that whether that page has been allocated
而值为0表示该页面是否已被分配。
from the physical memory or and 1 if it was allocated.
从物理内存中读取，如果已分配则返回1。
So if you want to find a page in physical memory you can allocate,
那么如果你想找到一个可以分配的物理内存页面，
you just find a 0 in this bit vector.
你刚刚在这个位向量中找到了一个0。
Now, what about the size of the pages?
现在，页面的尺寸呢？
If the pages are too large, again, all pages
如果页面太大，再次，所有页面。
are the same size.
大小相同。
What is the problem?
什么问题？(What is the problem?)
What is the problem if the pages are too large?
如果页面太大，会有什么问题？
[AUDIO OUT]
[音频关闭]
Wasty spice, internal fragmentation, excellent.
嗯，"Wasty spice"、"internal fragmentation"、"excellent"这几个词都是英文，不需要翻译。
So I buy it and add it on.
所以我买了它并添加上去。
And cost of context switching can be higher
而上下文切换的成本可能更高。
if you need to swap that page out.
如果你需要替换那个页面。
That's correct.
没错。
But yes, the main thing is about internal fragmentation.
但是，是的，主要问题是内部碎片化。
Because if you think about, if you have these pages,
因为如果你考虑一下，如果你有这些页面，
say you have a page of 1 gigabyte,
假设你有一个1千兆字节的页面，
if your program is only 1 megabyte,
如果你的程序只有1兆字节大小，
you waste enormous, most of the space.
你浪费了巨大的空间，大部分都是空着的。
So you want small pages.
所以你想要小页面。
OK?
好的。
The problem with the small pages,
小页面的问题是，
what is the problem with the small pages?
小页面有什么问题？
[AUDIO OUT]
[音频关闭]
Any guess?
有什么猜测吗？
[AUDIO OUT]
[音频关闭]
Lots of accounting, more translation is yes.
很多会计工作，更多的翻译是可以的。
Lots of accounting.
很多会计工作。
I wouldn't say more translations and larger page table.
我不会说更多的翻译和更大的页面表。
OK, you already know about it.
好的，你已经知道了。
Yes.
是的。
But it's accounting is hard.
但是会计很难。
You have to deal with more things.
你必须处理更多的事情。
Right.
对的。
And OK, so let's see.
好的，那么让我们来看看。
So now, how do you do the translation?
现在，你是如何进行翻译的呢？
But there are not many more translation because--
但是没有更多的翻译，因为--
in theory, right?
理论上，对吗？
Because you still need to-- every virtual address,
因为你仍然需要-每个虚拟地址，
you need to translate your physical address.
你需要翻译你的实际地址。
The little bit of truth of that, the higher overhead
那个小小的事实，开销越高
per translation could be.
每个翻译可能是这样的。
But the number of translation is basically the same.
但是翻译的数量基本上是相同的。
Yeah, works on cache can be that as well.
是的，缓存相关的工作也可以是这样的。
Yeah.
是的。
OK, so how is a translation works with paging?
好的，那么分页是如何与翻译一起工作的呢？
It's very similar with segmentation,
这与分割非常相似，
but with a few differences.
但是有一些不同之处。
So first of all, you have a page table.
首先，你有一个页表。
And the virtual address, as again, is in two parts.
而虚拟地址，同样地，由两部分组成。
We have a virtual page number and an offset.
我们有一个虚拟页号和一个偏移量。
But there is a difference.
但是有一个区别。
The offset is not added to a base address.
偏移量不会添加到基地址上。
The offset of the address remains the same.
地址的偏移量保持不变。
So with translation, when you use paging, what happens,
当你使用分页功能进行翻译时，会发生什么情况呢？
it's only the virtual page part.
这只是虚拟页面的一部分。
The first field changes, right?
第一个字段会改变，对吗？
A virtual page number is replaced
一个虚拟页号被替换了。
by a physical page number.
通过物理页码。
That's it.
就这样。
So the same like previously, the first bits, in this case,
所以和之前一样，这里的第一部分，
the virtual page number in the previous case
在之前的情况下，虚拟页号是多少？
was a segment number, are going to index in the page table.
是一个段号，将要在页表中进行索引。
But in the page table, what you are going to find,
但在页表中，你将会找到的是，
you have a page number, which is a physical page number.
你有一个页码，这是一个物理页码。
And you are going to take that physical page number,
然后你会将那个物理页码，
and you are going to concatenate with the offset
你将与偏移量连接在一起。
of the virtual address.
虚拟地址的含义。
So the offset of the physical address
物理地址的偏移量是多少？
and the offset of the physical address
和物理地址的偏移量
are the same, OK?
一样的，可以吗？
Typical page sizes are between 4 kilobytes and 16 kilobytes
典型的页面大小在4千字节到16千字节之间。
are quite small.
相当小。
4 kilobytes means what?
4 kilobytes means 4096 bytes.
12 bits, you need 12 bits.
12位，你需要12位。
And 16 kilobytes, you need another 14 bits, right?
16 kilobytes is equal to 16384 bytes. So, to convert it to bits, you would need an additional 14 bits.
So if you have even smaller pages, right?
所以如果你有更小的页面，对吗？
And this is where you see the number,
这是你看到数字的地方。
the problem with the small pages.
小页面的问题。
So you have a 32-bit address.
所以你有一个32位的地址。
And you are going to use 1 kilobyte pages.
你将使用1千字节的页面。
So you need 10 bits offset.
所以你需要10位的偏移量。
This is what you need, 10 bits offset.
这是你需要的，偏移量为10个位。
And therefore, the virtual page number, the number of bits
因此，虚拟页号，位数的数量
there is 22 bits, 32 minus 10, 22 bits.
有22位，32减去10，22位。
So therefore, the page table have 4 million sentences.
所以，页面表有四百万个句子。
Huge.
巨大的。
And just think about if you have 64 bits address.
而且想想如果你有64位的地址。
So in order to do that, for instance, you are--
所以为了做到这一点，例如，你是--
you are also going to not allocate space
你也不打算分配空间。
for the entire maximum size page table.
对于整个最大尺寸的页表。
So you are going to just grow this page table as you
所以你打算只是扩展这个页表，使其变得更大。
add more pages to it.
请给它添加更多页面。
And therefore, you are going to have in addition to the page
而且，除了这个页面之外，你还会有...
table pointer, which represent the start of the page table,
页表指针，它代表着页表的起始位置。
also the page table size, which is, as the name implies,
也包括页面表的大小，正如其名称所示，
the size of the page table, which can be increased
页表的大小可以增加。
as you add more tables, as you allocate more pages
随着您添加更多的表格，分配更多的页面。
and you are--
你是--
so that you allocate more entries,
为了让你分配更多的条目，
you add more entries to the page table.
你需要在页表中添加更多的条目。
Also, with each page, you are going
此外，每一页都会有你的去向。
to have a bunch of bits which represents some--
拥有一堆位，代表某些东西--
we are going to discuss them more a little bit later.
我们稍后会更详细地讨论它们。
So keep in mind about these bits.
所以记住这些要点。
We are going to give an example a few slides later.
我们将在几张幻灯片后给出一个例子。
So this is a very simple page table.
这是一个非常简单的页表。
You have a four-by space, so it's a trivial example.
你有一个四乘的空间，所以这是一个简单的例子。
You have this on the virtual memory.
你在谈论虚拟内存。
You have four pages starting from 0, 4, and 8.
你有四页，从0、4和8开始。
And then you have a page table only with three entries,
然后你只有一个包含三个条目的页表。
because you have three pages in the virtual memory.
因为你在虚拟内存中有三个页面。
So assume that the address space here
所以假设这里的地址空间
is has equivalent of 8 bits, so it's 64 bytes.
一个字节等于8位，所以它是64字节。
So the address, if you need for the page table,
所以地址，如果你需要用于页面表，
again, if you have four bits, you need only two bits
再说一遍，如果你有四个位，你只需要两个位。
to represent four bytes, to address four bytes.
表示四个字节，寻址四个字节。
So therefore, the last two bits represent the offset,
所以，最后两位表示偏移量。
and the first six bits represent what?
前六位代表什么？
Represent the page number.
代表页面编号。
OK, so if you want A, it's at the address 0 here.
好的，如果你想要A，它在这里的地址是0。
So if you want to translate the address 0,
那么如果你想翻译地址0，
then the page number identifies the first entry in the table.
然后页码标识了表格中的第一条目。
The first entry in the table contains four.
表格中的第一项包含四个。
So now four is a new physical page number,
所以现在四是一个新的物理页码。
so you are going to concatenate these four
所以你要将这四个连接起来
with the offset, which is 0.
偏移量是0。
So you are going to get 0x10.
所以你要得到0x10。
OK?
好的。
The same thing, similar things happen
同样的事情，类似的事情发生了。
if you want to access the first address, the address four,
如果你想访问第一个地址，即地址四，
the virtual address four.
虚拟地址四。
The virtual address four now is going
虚拟地址现在是四。
to lead you, because the offset is one,
带领你，因为偏移量是一。
is going to lead you to the second entry in the page table.
将会引导您到页表中的第二个条目。
The second entry in the page table contains three,
页表中的第二个条目包含三个，
so you are going to concatenate three with zero,
所以你要将三和零连接起来，
which is the offset.
偏移量是多少？
You are going to get to the address 0c, physical address,
你将到达地址0c，物理地址。
and so forth.
等等。
OK?
好的？
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
So question here, why was space size issues
所以问题在这里，为什么空间大小有问题？
in between 4 kilobytes and 16 kilobytes?
在4千字节和16千字节之间？
This is, again, always a trade-off.
这又是一个权衡取舍的问题。
The smaller the table, the smaller the page,
表越小，页面越小，
the smaller the internal fragmentation,
内部碎片越小，
so the less wasted space.
所以浪费的空间越少。
However, the smaller the page, the larger the page tables
然而，页面越小，页面表越大。
are, so therefore, it's much more context switching,
是的，因此，这样会导致更多的上下文切换。
actually, can be more expensive.
实际上，可能会更贵。
Good question.
好问题。
OK?
好的。
And these are some other translation.
这是一些其他的翻译。
Translating the address five, it's
翻译地址五，它是什么？
going to translate to the address in this case
将在这种情况下进行地址翻译。
is basically 117, and I think there is another example.
基本上是117，我认为还有另一个例子。
Nine is going-- sorry.
九要走了——抱歉。
Previous case, the address six was
之前的案例，地址是六。
translating to the address 116, and the second case,
将地址翻译为116，并且第二个案例。
the address nine is going to translate to address five.
地址九将被翻译为地址五。
No, physical address five.
不，物理地址是五。
[AUDIO OUT]
[音频关闭]
So there is an anonymous question
所以有一个匿名的问题
asking about if the 0x12345678 is the address,
询问0x12345678是否是地址。
could the first 123456 can be the offset?
第一个123456可以作为偏移量吗？
Now, again, the offset are the last bits in the address.
现在，再次，偏移量是地址中的最后几位。
OK?
好的。
So in this particular case, again, the offset,
在这种特殊情况下，再次提到偏移量，
if you look at the first one, example here, the offset,
如果你看一下第一个例子，这里的偏移量，
it's one, zero, are the black bits,
这是一个，零，是黑色的部分，
and the page number are the red bits.
并且页码是红色的部分。
So the offset is two in this case, and the page number,
所以在这种情况下，偏移量是2，页面编号是
it's one.
这是一个。
And page number one selects the second entry
并且第一页选择第二个条目。
in the page table, which is three, so it's one, one.
在页表中，有三个，所以是一个、一个。
And the offset remains one, zero,
偏移量仍然是一、零。
so now I have one, one, one, zero, which is basically e.
所以现在我有一个、一个、一个、零，基本上就是e。
[AUDIO OUT]
[音频关闭]
OK.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
What about sharing?
分享怎么样？
Well, if you want to share a page between processes,
好的，如果你想在进程之间共享一个页面，
these are not RPT-E's, right?
这些不是RPT-E的，对吗？
You just-- you have each of the processes
你只需要--你有每个过程
has its own page table, and if you
有自己的页表，并且如果你
want to share the same pages, then the corresponding entries
想要共享相同的页面，然后对应的条目。
are going to point to the same physical table.
将指向同一物理表。
That's it.
就这样。
[AUDIO OUT]
[音频关闭]
Very elegant.
非常优雅。
Where is page sharing used?
页面分享在哪里使用？
Kernel region of the processes.
进程的内核区域。
So of every-- so for the processes,
所以对于每一个--所以对于这些过程，
you have a kernel region, as you remember,
你有一个内核区域，就像你记得的那样。
so every process has the same--
所以每个过程都是一样的
all the processes, they have to see
所有的流程，他们都必须看到。
that you are going to share this code, the kernel code,
你打算分享这段代码，内核代码，
across all the processes, because the same code is not
在所有的流程中，因为相同的代码不是
going to change.
要改变了。
You can-- and by the way, this is protected.
你可以——顺便说一下，这是受保护的。
It's like the kernel will have--
这就像内核会有--
the process only can access at the user level
该过程只能在用户级别下访问。
when I'm talking about the kernel region.
当我谈论内核区域时。
I'm not talking about kernel region being
我不是在说内核区域被...
accessed by the process.
被进程访问。
I'm talking about the kernel regions associated
我在谈论与内核区域相关的内容。
with the process, which is accessed by the kernel
通过内核访问的进程
during the context switching.
在上下文切换期间。
During different processes running the same binary,
在运行相同二进制文件的不同进程中，
you don't need to duplicate that because the code is read only.
你不需要复制那个，因为这段代码是只读的。
User level libraries, like I mentioned,
用户级别的库，就像我之前提到的，
or even sharing the data between--
或者甚至在之间共享数据--
you can share the data between the processes.
你可以在进程之间共享数据。
You can use a shared memory.
你可以使用共享内存。
So this is another example.
这是另一个例子。
This is a summary of paging.
这是一个分页的摘要。
On the left-hand side, you have the virtual memory view.
在左侧，您可以看到虚拟内存视图。
On the right-hand side, you have the physical memory view.
在右侧，您可以看到物理内存视图。
And in the middle, you have the page table.
而在中间，你有页表。
You see that many entries in the tables are null,
你看到表格中有很多空值。
but this is a full page table.
但这是一个整页的表格。
And here, we are assuming an 8-bits address.
这里，我们假设使用8位地址。
And now, the offset are the last three bits.
现在，偏移量是最后三位。
So the base size is 2 power 3, so it's 8 bytes.
所以基本大小是2的3次方，所以是8字节。
And the page number is 5 bits.
并且页码是5位。
So you are going to have 2 power 5.
所以你打算有2的5次方的力量。
You have 32 entries in the page table up to.
您的页表上有32个条目。
OK.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
So now, the one thing--
所以现在，唯一的一件事是--
and on the right-hand side, you have, again,
在右侧，你再次有
like the physical memory.
喜欢物理内存。
So one thing here I just want to show you, and earlier on,
所以这里有一件事我想要向你展示，而且之前，
I said that, well, the stack--
我说过，嗯，堆栈--
how the stack and the heap grows here.
这里的堆栈和堆是如何增长的。
So now, the stack, again, grows downwards,
所以现在，栈再次向下增长，
so grows going to lower addresses.
所以增长将会降低地址。
And you see here, the stack, it's on the right-hand side.
你看到了吗，这里是堆栈，它在右边。
And with what I represented here, with the gray,
而我在这里所代表的，是灰色的，
the pages with gray are all OK, are all reallocated.
灰色的页面都是正常的，都已重新分配。
So only the pages which are white are not allocated yet.
所以只有白色的页面还没有被分配。
So let's see what happens and how
那么让我们看看会发生什么以及如何发展。
you are going to grow the stack.
你将要扩大技术栈。
So now, the problem is that, let's say
现在，问题是，假设
that I want to grow the stack by two pages.
我想要将堆栈增加两页。
I decide to grow the stack by two pages
我决定将堆栈增加两页。
in the virtual memory.
在虚拟内存中。
The virtual memory, I can very conveniently grow the stack
虚拟内存，我可以非常方便地扩展堆栈。
because I have enough space in the virtual memory.
因为我在虚拟内存中有足够的空间。
However, in the physical memory, if I'm
然而，在物理内存中，如果我...
going to try to grow it, I can allocate another page.
我打算尝试种植它，我可以再分配一页。
You can allocate another page.
你可以分配另一页。
Maybe you have only room for another page
也许你只有空间再加一页。
there if you want to allocate contiguously
如果你想要连续分配的话，可以在那里进行。
the pages to the stack.
将页面放到堆栈上。
But the point is a page with a translation
但是重点是一个有翻译的页面。
that these pages do not need to be allocated contiguously.
这些页面不需要连续分配。
So therefore, the only thing you can do,
所以，你能做的唯一的事情是，
the only thing you need to do, you
唯一需要你做的事情，你需要
need to find room for two other pages.
需要找到两个其他页面的空间。
And you are going to allocate these pages for the stack.
你将为堆栈分配这些页面。
But again, they don't need to be contiguous.
但是再次强调，它们不需要连续。
Whatever is contiguous in the virtual memory
无论在虚拟内存中相邻的是什么
doesn't need to be contiguous in the physical memory.
不需要在物理内存中连续。
OK.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
So now the biggest problem and the challenge, the table size,
所以现在最大的问题和挑战是桌子的尺寸。
if you're in the simplest version,
如果你处于最简单的版本中，
in the simple instantiation, in the simplest implementation,
在简单的实例化中，在最简单的实现中，
the type of size repeats.
尺寸的类型重复。
It's equal with the number of pages in the virtual memory.
这与虚拟内存中的页面数量相等。
And this can be absolutely huge.
这可能是非常巨大的。
So let's give Satek an example.
那么让我们给Satek举个例子。
So you have 32 bits address space.
所以你有32位的地址空间。
So you have 4 gigabytes address, virtual address space.
所以你有4GB的地址，虚拟地址空间。
And these are just the units for you to remember.
这些只是你需要记住的单位。
So the one thing to remember here and one confusion
所以这里要记住的一件事和一个困惑是什么？
I've seen often is that when you are going--
我经常看到的是，当你要去的时候--
when you are talking about the memory,
当你谈论记忆时，
we are talking about the power of two units.
我们正在讨论两个单位的力量。
So 1 kilobyte is 2 power 10.
所以1千字节是2的10次方。
1 megabyte, 2 power 10.
1 megabyte is equal to 2 to the power of 10.
And gigabyte, 2 power 10.
并且是千兆字节，2的10次方。
When we are talking about bandwidth and how much
当我们谈论带宽以及有多少的时候
capacity, network capacity, we are talking in power of 10.
容量，网络容量，我们是以10的幂次进行讨论。
1 kilobyte or 1 kilobit, it's 1,000 bits.
1千字节或1千比特，都是1,000比特。
1 gigabyte, 1 gigabit represent what?
1 gigabyte represents 1千兆字节, and 1 gigabit represents 1千兆位.
It's 1 billion bits.
这是10亿比特。
So now, assume the typical page size is 4 kilobytes.
那么现在，假设典型的页面大小为4千字节。
So it's 2 power 10.
所以是2的10次方。
We need 10 bits to address any byte in a 4 kilobyte page.
我们需要10位来寻址4千字节页面中的任何字节。
So therefore, OK.
所以，好的。
Sorry, we need 12, what I'm talking about.
抱歉，我们需要12个，我在说什么。
If the page is 4 kilobytes, this means 2 power 12.
如果页面大小为4千字节，这意味着2的12次方。
So therefore, I need 12 bits to address any byte within a page.
所以，因此，我需要12位来寻址页面内的任何字节。
So the offset is 10 bits.
偏移量为10位。
And therefore, if the offset is 10 bits,
因此，如果偏移量为10位，
the page number, it's 32 minus 12 is 20 bits.
页码，它是32减去12等于20位。
So now, the page table size can have as big as 4 megabytes.
所以现在，页表的大小可以达到4兆字节。
Right?
对吗？
Why is 4 megabytes?
为什么是4兆字节？
Because each of the entry in the page table
因为页表中的每个条目
needs to have 20 bits.
需要有20位。
And then you are also going to have some other, like you see,
然后你还会有其他的，就像你看到的那样。
some other flags associated.
一些其他相关的旗帜。
So you have 32 bits for each entry.
所以每个条目有32位。
So it's 4 bytes, and you have 2 power 20 entries.
所以它是4个字节，你有2的20次方个条目。
So it's 4 megabytes total.
所以总共是4兆字节。
So this was a lot of memory.
这是很多回忆。
And now, think about this was in the past
现在，想想这是过去的事情。
when you have 32 bits was the standard,
当32位成为标准时，
but now the standard is 64 bits.
但现在的标准是64位。
There is no way, right?
没有办法，对吗？
If you try to do the same thing here,
如果你在这里尝试做同样的事情，
you are going to have 30 exabytes, which
你将拥有30艾字节的存储空间，这是一个非常庞大的数字。
is only for the page table.
仅适用于页表。
Actually, you don't have enough physical memory
实际上，你的物理内存不足。
to store that page table.
将该页表存储起来。
This is really a lot of space.
这真的是很大的空间。
So what is the solution here?
那么这里的解决方案是什么呢？
Right?
对吗？
And by the way, all this space is empty.
顺便说一下，所有这些空间都是空的。
Most of this-- no, no, not all of this.
大部分的这个——不，不，不是全部的。
Most of this space is empty because you don't
大部分空间都是空的，因为你没有填写任何内容。
have as many page tables.
拥有尽可能多的页表。
You have very few page tables, right?
你的页表很少，对吗？
So which are actually allocated.
所以哪些实际上已经分配了。
So what is a--
那么，这是什么——
so this is a big problem, and we are looking for a solution.
这是一个大问题，我们正在寻找解决方案。
So a little bit of a discussion about page table
关于页表的一点讨论。
before going forward.
继续之前。
So what do you need to switch on the page table?
所以你需要打开页面表吗？
When a context switch happens, what do you need to do?
当发生上下文切换时，你需要做什么？
You need to have a page for the table point--
你需要为表格添加一个页面。
the page table pointer, so the beginning of the page table
页表指针，即页表的起始位置。
and the limit, the size of the page table.
和限制，页面表的大小。
Again, remember about the dual mode operation, because these
再次提醒一下双模操作，因为这些
space tables can be only modified and accessed
空间表只能被修改和访问。
by the kernel.
由内核。
You cannot let an application access these space tables,
你不能让应用程序访问这些空间表。
because then they can change the page table,
因为这样他们就可以更改页面表。
and they can point to anywhere, to any other address,
而且它们可以指向任何地方，任何其他地址，
including the kernel or the address of other applications.
包括内核或其他应用程序的地址。
And now let's look at the pros and cons.
现在让我们来看看利与弊。
On the pros side, it's a very simple memory allocation.
在优点方面，这是一个非常简单的内存分配。
Remember, you have a bit vector, 0 or 1,
记住，你有一个位向量，0或1，
whether the page is allocated or not in the physical memory.
页面是否在物理内存中分配。
The bit vector contains one bit for each page
位向量中包含每个页面的一个位。
in the physical memory.
在物理内存中。
Easy to share.
易于分享。
The cons we've seen.
我们看到的缺点。
If the address space is very sparse,
如果地址空间非常稀疏，
the page table can be huge.
页表可能非常庞大。
So again, if the page table is big,
那么，如果页表很大的话，
then you need also probably to context switch.
那么你可能还需要进行上下文切换。
You cannot keep all the time in the memory.
你不能一直把所有的时间都记在脑子里。
If the process is a page table of a process,
如果这个过程是一个进程的页表，
if the process is now switched off
如果现在该过程已经关闭了。
and is no longer using the CPU, you may want--
并且不再使用中央处理器，你可能想要--
it was preempted.
被提前安排了。
You may want to take the page table of that process
你可能想要获取该进程的页表。
and swap on the disk.
并在磁盘上进行交换。
But if that is large, then the overhead is very large.
但如果那个很大，那么开销就非常大。
So the TLDR here, the page table,
所以这里的TLDR是，页表，
the paging is a technique with elegant solution.
分页是一种具有优雅解决方案的技术。
Very simple to implement.
非常简单实施。
Provides low internal fragmentation
提供低内部碎片化
if the pages are small.
如果页面很小。
On the downside, the problem we encounter
在不利的一面，我们遇到的问题是
is because the page tables can be huge.
是因为页面表可能非常庞大。
So what is the solution?
那么解决方案是什么呢？
Well, the solution is you know, you
好的，解决方案就是你知道的，你
represent the same technique, right?
代表相同的技术，对吗？
You recursively do it.
你递归地做这件事。
And it's multilevel paging.
并且它是多级分页。
Look, if the page tables are very large,
看，如果页表非常大，
then why don't we have a page table for that page table,
那为什么我们不为那个页表再创建一个页表呢？
right?
对吗？
Or you can combine paging segmentations, OK?
或者你可以将分页分段组合起来，好吗？
So and these are the two solutions.
这是两个解决方案。
Segment mapping, you are going to have segments.
分段映射，你将会有分段。
And in the segments, you are going to have--
在这些片段中，你将会有--
you know, you page the segments.
你知道，你分页了段落。
And then in the page tables, you are
然后在页表中，你是什么意思？
going to page the page tables.
要访问页表。
And let's look about how this is working.
让我们来看看这是如何运作的。
So the core, remember that the page table
所以核心是，记住页面表。
is a map between the virtual page number
是虚拟页号之间的映射。
and the physical page number.
和物理页码。
This is what it is.
这就是它的样子。
So a simple page table is just a lookup table.
所以一个简单的页表就是一个查找表。
VPN, the virtual page number, it's
VPN, 虚拟页码，它是一种网络工具，用于在互联网上建立安全的连接。
an index in this table which contains a physical page
这个表中的索引包含一个物理页。
number.
数字。
By the way, what other map structures can you think of?
顺便问一下，你还能想到哪些其他的地图结构呢？
There are many of them, trees, hash table, and so forth.
有很多东西，树、哈希表等等。
But obviously, these are more complicated.
但显然，这些更加复杂。
More complicated means higher overhead,
更复杂意味着更高的开销。
even though they can have slower storage overhead.
即使它们可能具有较慢的存储开销。
The beautiful things about the page table
关于页表的美好之处
is very quick to access, right?
非常快速地访问，对吗？
It's just an index.
这只是一个索引。
If you use the trees and hash tables,
如果你使用树和哈希表，
and we'll see about that.
我们会看看的。
They are much more space efficient.
它们更加节省空间。
You don't need to maintain all the entries, which you know, for it, there is no table,
你不需要维护所有的条目，你知道的，对此，没有表格。
but accessing those is much more expensive.
但是访问那些的费用要高得多。
There's a trade-off here.
这里存在一个权衡。
So one simple solution is like we mentioned is to have to do the problem of having very
因此，一个简单的解决方案就像我们之前提到的那样，是要解决存在非常的问题。
big page tables is to page these page tables.
大页表是为了分页这些页表。
And basically, here is a two-level page table.
基本上，这是一个两级页表。
And here is that instead of now the address has three fields.
而现在，地址有三个字段，而不是一个。
At the end is the offset like before, no difference here.
最后的偏移量与之前一样，这里没有任何区别。
But what was previously corresponding to the page number, now you split into two fields,
但之前对应于页码的内容，现在被拆分为两个字段，
which corresponds to virtual page numbers or page indexes for the two-level pages.
这对应于两级页面的虚拟页号或页面索引。
So the first 10 bits in this case represents a virtual p1 index.
所以在这种情况下，前10位表示一个虚拟的p1索引。
So indexing the first level table, page table.
索引第一级表，页表。
And this is going to take you-- it's going to contain an address to a page containing
并且这将会花费您一些时间——它将包含一个指向包含地址的页面的链接。
the page table entries at the second level.
第二级的页表项。
OK?
好的。
So in order to compute now the entire physical address, use a p1 index to find the address
所以现在为了计算整个物理地址，使用p1索引来找到地址。
of the page containing the physical page number, which is stored in the second level.
页面包含物理页号，该物理页号存储在第二级中。
And this physical page number is going to be concatenated with the offset like before.
这个物理页码将会像之前一样与偏移量连接起来。
And now you have the physical address.
现在你有了实际地址。
OK?
好的。
So it's the same thing, the same thing.
所以这是同样的事情，同样的事情。
The only difference is that now you split the physical page number into a part which
唯一的区别是现在你将物理页码分成了两部分，一部分是
is going to index into a page table, first-level page table, which contains the address of
将要索引到一个页表，一级页表，其中包含地址的
a second-level page table.
一个二级页表。
And the second field in this page number is going to index in the second-level page table.
这个页面编号的第二个字段将会在二级页表中进行索引。
And at that entry, corresponding entry, you are going to have physical page number.
在那个入口处，对应的条目上会有实际的页码。
And you can have many more levels.
而且你可以有更多的级别。
So now these are some announcements.
现在是一些公告。
We are just 15 minutes before the class, so ends.
我们离上课还有15分钟，所以快结束了。
But here are some announcements.
但是这里有一些公告。
So you release a midterm score.
所以你发布了一份期中成绩。
And please check Piazza for grading policies.
请查看Piazza上的评分政策。
I think you did quite well.
我认为你做得相当不错。
The scores and the distribution is very much in line with that of the past midterms in
分数和分布与过去期中考试非常一致。
the recent years.
近年来。
The Project 2 Design Document, remember, is due by this at the end of this Friday.
项目2的设计文档，记住，截止时间是本周五的最后。
And the Homework 3 is due on Sunday at the end of the day.
并且作业3的截止日期是周日的最后一天。
So if you want an extra credit point, please feel free to meet semester survey and check
所以如果你想要额外的学分，请随时参加学期调查并检查。
on Piazza for details.
请在Piazza上查看详情。
OK?
好的。
So it's free, free extra credit.
所以它是免费的，免费的额外学分。
The next lecture, I'll be out of town.
下一堂课，我将不在城里。
And Nathan Pemberton, who's a senior PhD student, which is expert both in architectures and
Nathan Pemberton是一位高年级的博士生，他在架构和技术方面都很专业。
systems, is going to teach this class.
系统，将要教授这门课。
He's a fantastic teacher, fun.
他是一个很棒的老师，很有趣。
I really urge you to attend his lecture.
我真的强烈建议你去参加他的讲座。
They are going to be a lot more fun than my lectures.
他们会比我的讲座更有趣。
So he's a great presenter.
所以他是一个很棒的演讲者。
So remember that I mentioned to you now that in a page table entry, besides a physical
所以记住我现在跟你提到的，在页表项中，除了一个物理地址之外，还有一个有效位。
page number, we are going also to have some bits.
页码，我们还会有一些片段。
And here is an example.
这是一个例子。
So let's take our previous examples in which you are going to have an offset of the-- you
所以让我们来看看之前的例子，其中你将会有一个偏移量--你
have a 32-bits address.
我有一个32位的地址。
The offset is 12 bits.
偏移量为12位。
So the physical page number is 20 bits.
所以物理页号是20位。
OK?
好的。
So now for in a page table, what you need, you need the physical page number, which is
所以现在在页表中，你需要什么，你需要物理页号，也就是
these 20 bits.
这20个比特。
So what about the rest of the rest of the rest of the rest of the bits?
那么剩下的剩下的剩下的剩下的部分呢？
So for the rest of the 12 bits, you are going to have a bunch of flags, which are used--
所以在剩下的12位中，你将会有一系列的标志位，这些标志位被用来--
so you have different use.
所以你有不同的用途。
You can use it in different ways.
你可以以不同的方式使用它。
But here is an example.
但是这里有一个例子。
And this is from Intel Architecture.
这是来自英特尔架构的产品。
So these are examples about these bits.
这些是关于这些位的例子。
And we are going to start from the least significant bits.
我们将从最低有效位开始。
0 is p.
0是页码。
This is present.
这是礼物。
It's the same as valid.
这与有效是一样的。
Is the page present in physical memory or not?
这个页面在物理内存中存在吗？
W, writable.
W, 可写的。
Can you write on this page or not?
你能在这页上写吗？
If it's 0, then it's read only.
如果是0，那么它是只读的。
U is user accessible.
U是用户可访问的。
Is this page accessible only by user?
这个页面只能由用户访问吗？
OK.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
PWT, page write transparent.
PWT，页面写入透明。
This is related with a cache.
这与缓存有关。
Typically you have caches to reduce the latency to access the data.
通常你会使用缓存来减少访问数据的延迟。
And when you have caches, the problem, the question is about how you are going to update
当你有缓存时，问题就在于你如何进行更新。
the physical memory, the data in the physical memory.
物理内存，物理内存中的数据。
And there are two ways here we are going to learn.
这里有两种学习方式。
But one way is that whenever we are going to access and we are going to write to the
但有一种方法是，每当我们要访问并写入时，我们可以将其转换为中文。
cache and modify the data, we are also going to modify the data in the physical memory.
缓存并修改数据，我们还将修改物理内存中的数据。
And this is page writes transparent.
这一页是透明的。
PCD is page cache disabled.
PCD是页面缓存禁用。
You cannot cache the pages.
你不能缓存这些页面。
A, it's access page has been accessed recently.
A, 它的访问页面最近被访问过。
This is used also for caching.
这也用于缓存。
If it's accessed recently, and the next two are the same, also for caching.
如果最近访问过，并且接下来的两个也是相同的，也是为了缓存。
You want to know whether the page was accessed recently and whether it's dirty, whether it
您想知道页面是否最近被访问过以及是否有更新，是否脏了，是否
was written.
这是一个需要翻译的句子，请问您希望将其翻译成中文还是英文呢？
And the physical memory associated with physical memory was not updated.
而与物理内存相关联的物理内存并未更新。
So you need to know about that.
所以你需要了解那个。
And then you are going, we may decide to page that to-- this is-- OK, how do I say?
然后你要去，我们可能决定将其分页——这是——好的，我该怎么说呢？
So these two bits, the only thing you need to know now, are used when deciding what page
所以这两个位，现在你需要知道的唯一事情，是在决定页面时使用的。
to swap out of the memory to make room for new pages.
将内存中的页面换出，为新页面腾出空间。
Fundamentally, you do not want to swap out a page of a process which will be accessed
基本上，你不想交换一个将被访问的进程的页面。
immediately.
立即。
And OK, that's a question.
好的，那是一个问题。
The PCD means-- the question is that PCD means-- it's about what PCD means.
PCD是“Pitch Circle Diameter”的缩写，意思是“螺距圆直径”。关于PCD的含义是什么。
The PCD means that the page is not cached.
PCD表示页面未缓存。
And again, the reason you may choose to not cache a page is that, for instance, in multiprocessor
而且，你选择不缓存页面的原因可能是，例如，在多处理器系统中，
systems, multi-core systems, when you have concurrency on the same page, you have a page
系统，多核系统，当你在同一页上有并发时，你就有了一个页面。
which is shared to different processes which run on different processors.
这是共享给在不同处理器上运行的不同进程的。
And they can concurrently access that page.
他们可以同时访问那个页面。
And if you want to update the page, if it's cached, each processor cached, then you have
如果您想更新页面，如果它被缓存了，每个处理器都被缓存了，那么您就有...
a cache coherency problem.
一个缓存一致性问题。
And if you want to simplify that problem, if you want to remove that problem, you can
而且，如果你想简化那个问题，如果你想消除那个问题，你可以...
say, OK, this page is never going to be cached.
说，好的，这个页面永远不会被缓存。
OK.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
So example of how to use PTEs, invalid PTEs is that-- again, even this one can imply different
使用PTE（页表项）和无效的PTE的示例是——再次强调，即使这个示例可能会有不同的含义。
things in the operating system besides how to use these flags.
除了如何使用这些标志之外，操作系统中还有其他的东西。
So one-- yeah.
所以，是的。
And one we use is that-- which I didn't mention-- is that the address space is actually not valid.
我们使用的另一个方法是——我之前没有提到的——就是地址空间实际上是无效的。
Right?
对吗？
It doesn't-- it's not allocated.
它没有被分配。
But another way is basically, say, the page direct-- that page is not in the memory.
但另一种方式基本上是，比如说，页面直接——那个页面不在内存中。
It's on the disk.
它在磁盘上。
Right?
对吗？
In that case, you need-- it's a trap to the operating system exception.
在这种情况下，你需要注意——这是一个陷阱，会导致操作系统异常。
It results into a trap to the operating system.
这导致操作系统陷入了一个陷阱。
And the operating system is going to figure out where is the page is stored and is going
而操作系统将会找出页面存储的位置，并且
to bring it to memory.
将其记起。
And this is going to be used by the main page.
这将被主页使用。
We are going to learn about that.
我们将要学习关于那个的内容。
Another use here is about copy on write for the PTE.
这里的另一个用途是关于PTE的写时复制。
So basically, when you fork, remember that the fork-- when you fork a process, a fork
所以基本上，当你分叉时，记住分叉--当你分叉一个进程时，一个分叉
process copy actually is a parent process.
进程副本实际上是一个父进程。
Right?
对吗？
It has everything.
它拥有一切。
And now the question is, do you want to copy it right away?
现在的问题是，你想立即复制它吗？
Right?
对吗？
And are you going to copy everything?
你打算把一切都复制吗？
And it's not smart to do it because, for instance, the code of the process-- of the parent process
而且这样做是不明智的，因为比如说，父进程的代码--
is the same code you are-- the child process is going to execute.
你要执行的代码是相同的吗？子进程将要执行它。
The code is read only, so you don't need to copy it.
这段代码是只读的，所以你不需要复制它。
But the same is also true about the data.
但是数据也是如此。
Right?
对吗？
Do you want to copy-- to move that-- to copy the data from the process address space to
你想复制--移动那个--将数据从进程地址空间复制到哪里？
the child address space?
孩子的地址空间？
Well, the answer there is that only if the child-- ideally, only if the child accesses
好的，答案是只有当孩子——理想情况下，只有当孩子能够访问到。
it.
这个。
Right?
对吗？
And writes it.
然后写下来。
Right?
对吗？
So when-- so that's what-- so initially, when you are going to create-- because you want
所以当--那就是--最初，当你要创建--因为你想要
to reduce the overhead to create a deforca process, the fork process can share the entire
为了减少创建deforca进程的开销，fork进程可以共享整个进程空间。
address-- the entire address space to the parent process.
地址--整个地址空间给父进程。
OK?
好的。
So the reads are very-- the reads are going to the same memory.
所以这些读取操作非常——这些读取操作都指向同一块内存。
It's memory efficient.
它的内存使用效率很高。
It's fast.
很快。
Right?
对吗？
To fork.
分叉。
And but then the only one you can start doing it is when you write it.
然而，你只能在写下来的时候才能开始做。
So when you write a page, now, only now, you are going to create a copy of that page for
你写一页的时候，现在，只有现在，你要为那一页创建一个副本。
the child.
这个孩子。
And now the child can write and read from that copy.
现在孩子可以从那份复印件上写和读了。
But as long as you want to read, you can read from the same memory-- physical memory-- which
但只要你想读取，你可以从相同的内存中读取——物理内存——其中
is shared with the parent.
与父母共享。
Another use case here, it's a zero fill on demand.
这里还有另一个用例，它是按需进行零填充。
So say you allocate, say, 10 gigabytes of memory, and you want to initialize to zero.
所以假设你分配了10GB的内存，你想要将其初始化为零。
That initialization can take seconds, many seconds, just to do this initialization.
初始化可能需要几秒钟，甚至几十秒，只是为了进行这个初始化。
So you don't want to pay the overhead then when you are going to allocation.
所以你不想在分配时支付额外费用。
So instead what you can do, you can do zero fill on demand.
所以，你可以选择进行零填充操作。
So the OS knows that this page needs to be zero, but initially doesn't make them zero.
所以操作系统知道这个页面需要被清零，但最初并没有将它们清零。
It makes them zero only when you access that page.
只有当你访问那个页面时，它们才会变成零。
And that's perfectly fine because you amortize zeroing it.
这是完全可以的，因为你可以将其摊销为零。
Or even better, maybe the application is not going to ever touch every byte which is allocating
或者更好的是，也许这个应用程序永远不会触及分配的每一个字节。
these 10 gigabytes.
这是10个千兆字节。
So it's, again, some smart ways to use this PD.
所以，再次说，这是一些使用这个PD的聪明方法。
So sharing with multiple level pages, you can see here you have two processes.
所以在多级页面共享时，你可以看到这里有两个进程。
Each process has its own page table hierarchy.
每个进程都有自己的页表层次结构。
And the first level page, you can see for each process, it's pointed from-- you have
而且在第一级页面上，你可以看到每个流程都是从哪里指向的--你有
the page table pointer and page table pointer prime for the two page tables, different page
页面表指针和页面表指针主要用于两个页面表，这两个页面表是不同的。
tables, first level page tables.
表格，一级页面表格。
And then each of them, they have point to second level page tables.
然后每个页面都有指向第二级页表的指针。
And what you can see here is that some of the second level page tables are shared.
这里可以看到一些二级页表是共享的。
And obviously, all the pages to which entries in the shared page tables point to are also
而且显然，所有共享页表中条目所指向的页面也是这样。
shared.
分享的。
And finally, you remember, we started with solving this problem that the page tables
最后，你记得，我们开始解决这个问题，即页面表的问题。
can become extremely large.
可以变得非常大。
And if we have-- but many of the entries from these huge page tables are null, so contains
而且如果我们有--但是这些巨大的页表中的许多条目都是空的，所以包含什么呢？
no information.
没有信息。
And we said that the two level page table is going to solve that, address that problem,
我们说过，双级页表将解决这个问题，解决那个问题。
or at least alleviate that problem.
或者至少缓解那个问题。
And here is an example.
这是一个例子。
So if you remember, this is an example, and let me just try to go back here.
所以如果你还记得的话，这只是一个例子，让我试着回到这里。
So this is a previous example.
这是一个之前的例子。
So this is an example in which you are going to have, if you can see, this was a one level
所以这是一个例子，在这个例子中，如果你能看到的话，这是一个一级的。
table.
桌子。
So you have, I think, 72 entries.
所以你有，我想，72个条目。
Many of these entries are null.
这些条目中有很多是空的。
And this is a corresponding example.
这是一个相应的例子。
This is a corresponding example.
So you can see and you can count.
所以你可以看到，你可以数数。
You have much fewer-- it requires fewer-- less storage for storing these page tables.
你需要更少的存储空间来存储这些页表。
And certainly, you have much more fewer null entries.
当然，你有更少的空白条目。
So let me just continue.
那么让我继续吧。
We have just a few more minutes.
我们只剩下几分钟了。
And this also shows you about how the translation is done.
这也向你展示了翻译是如何进行的。
So in this particular case, we have, for the first level page table, we use three bits.
所以在这个特定的情况下，我们使用三位来表示第一级页表。
For the second level, two bits.
第二级，两位。
And for the offset, three bits.
并且对于偏移量，使用三个位。
So in the best case scenario, the size of the page tables is the number of pages used
所以在最理想的情况下，页面表的大小就是所使用的页面数量。
by the program in the virtual memory, unlike the previous case in which the number of pages
通过虚拟内存中的程序，与之前的情况不同，其中页面的数量
was the one available in the physical memory.
是在物理内存中可用的那一个。
The price to pay here is that you have one more additional memory access, because you
这里需要付出的代价是你需要多进行一次内存访问，因为你
need to index on both page tables at both levels.
需要在两个级别的页表上进行索引。
So how about about segments, segments and pages?
关于segments、segments和pages，有什么问题吗？
This is another way to do it.
这是另一种方法来做。
We have two level tables, but another way to solve similar problems is to combine segmentation
我们有两个层级表，但解决类似问题的另一种方法是将分割合并起来。
with paging.
带有分页。
So in this case, again, you have the address is split into three fields.
所以在这种情况下，你再次将地址分成了三个字段。
But the first field represents a segment number.
但是第一个字段代表的是段号。
The second field represents a virtual page number within that segment.
第二个字段表示该段内的虚拟页号。
And then you have the offset.
然后你还有偏移量。
So it's a very similar approach.
所以这是一个非常相似的方法。
Is again here, what do you need to save and store when context switching?
再次在这里，当进行上下文切换时，你需要保存和存储什么？
You need to store the segment table, you need to store the page table for that process.
你需要存储段表，你需要为该进程存储页表。
How do you share the data across different segments when you have these both segments
当你有这两个不同的部分时，你如何在它们之间共享数据？
and paging?
翻译结果：和分页呢？
It's the same very similar way.
这是同样非常相似的方式。
You are going to have from two different processes, they can share the pages by simply having
你将会从两个不同的流程中获得，它们可以通过简单地共享页面来实现。
the base by sharing the segment.
通过共享段落来建立基础。
If you want to send a bunch of pages, you are going to put all these pages in the same
如果你想发送一堆页面，你需要把所有这些页面放在同一个文件夹中。
segment and you are going to share the segment.
分段，你将要分享这个分段。
So let me do this one last slide and then I'm going to stop here.
那么让我做最后一张幻灯片，然后我就停在这里。
So when you have multi-level translation pages, what are the pros and cons?
当你有多级翻译页面时，有哪些优缺点呢？
So the big pro is that you get to is much less space for the page tables.
所以最大的优点是你可以为页面表节省很多空间。
That's it.
就这样。
So the paging themselves, they have the big advantage that it's fixed size, so they retain
所以分页本身有一个很大的优势，那就是它们是固定大小的，因此它们保留了
the simplicity.
简单。
You have no external fragmentation, you have only internal fragmentation.
你没有外部碎片，只有内部碎片。
The cons is that the page tables can be huge because they need to be continuous because
缺点是页表可能会很大，因为它们需要连续。
you need to index into that.
你需要对其进行索引。
And therefore you need to have multiple level of tables in order to get the memory allocation,
因此，您需要有多个层级的表格才能进行内存分配。
to get efficient memory allocation for the page tables.
为了获得页面表的高效内存分配。
But the big problem is that now you need to have multiple lookups for translation because
但是一个大问题是现在你需要进行多次查询来进行翻译，因为
you need to have a lookup for each level, for each page level.
你需要为每个层级、每个页面层级都设置查找功能。
So let's stop here and again, please attend Nathan's lecture on Thursday and I'll see
你好，让我们在这里停下来。请再次参加Nathan在星期四的讲座，我会去看的。
you next Monday.
你下周一。
Thanks.
谢谢。
So we are done.
我们完成了。
Let me just stop recording.
让我停止录音。